Zak Shafi

IT Service Desk Analyst / Desktop Support Engineer

London E.1 5LS | Mobile: +44 (0)7746 256848 | Email: zak.shafi@hotmail.com | Security Clearance: Basic Disclosure

Personal Profile

A highly energetic, enthusiastic and dependable individual who excels in challenging and competitive environments. Previous work experience shows ability to work on own initiative. Ability to assess organizational needs and implement administrative procedures. IT professional with years of background in system administration, hardware and software troubleshooting and network management for various small businesses as well as large ITIL based organisations. Excellent communication skills. A self-starter with ability to learn new applications quickly. Proficiencies in different IT fields related applications and platforms. Adept at reading, writing, and interpreting technical documentation and procedure manuals

Key Qualities and Skills

- Support 7, 10 & Server 2008R2, 2012R2
- Active Directory and Infrastructure Support
- Backup and Data Recovery Management
- Remote Desktop Support

- Experience of migrations and office moves
- Exchange Server 2010/13/0365 Management
- VDI Citrix and vWorkspace
- Knowledge of Ms Office 2010,2013,2016/0365

Recent Achievements

Oversee and migrate a high priority satellite office of 280 users during initial handover of I.T. services from Southwark to LGA Digital Services.

Migration of 4 sites from Office 2010 to Office 365. Converting offline document storage onto a SharePoint site with various levels of group permissions. Configure and upgrade of all client pcs to Win 10. Train resident 2 IT staff members on how to support Office 365 using the Admin Portal.

Work History

Renovation Period 2018 - Oct 2019

Personal time off Vasterbotten County, Sweden

Renovation of our home we have in North of Sweden before selling.

0365 Migration Support Engineer

5th FebOct 2018 - 4th May 2018

Client: robAtkinson.net Ltd

London Bridge, London (4mths)

Responsible for supporting technical migrations from Exchange 2013 to Office 365 in a Hybrid Exchange Migration. Execute, manage and lead a set of customers through the technical process and resolve customer deployment issues.

Act as a technical escalation point to the tier two support team for incidents requests when required.

Remote & On-Site Technical Support Officer

2nd Oct 2017 - 31st Jan 2018

Client: LGA ICT Shared Services

Wembley Park, London (4mths)

Responsible for and dealing with support issues across Desktop, Server and Network technologies for around 10,000 users across Brent, Lewisham and Southwark Councils. A variation of Managed Services and On-Site support. Some Project work which was part of the 'take-over' of Southwark IT Service Operations. Main duties included:

- Monitoring active SLAs, and KPIs (ITSM Hornbill) within ITIL aware procedures.
- Thick (Win 7) and Thin Client (Citrix XenDesktop and Dell vWorkspace) Support
- Active Directory/Exchange including new starter set-up, leavers and group policy management.
- 2nd line support of BAU and various Cloud Based Technologies

IT Support Officer - Umbrella (UK)

Sept 2016 - Sept 2017

Providing IT Support to various SME's which includes Server 2008r2, 2012r2 Active Directory Domain Services, Accounts Administration, DNS and DHCP Administration, Backups, WinTel 7,10 Desktop Support, Hardware and Software installations/troubleshooting. Remote Support as well as Floorwalking on-site.

IT Contractor-BlueberryMobil (Sweden)

Oct 2004 - Jan 2016

Client: Inseal Ltd (Manufacturers)

Xenshen, China (3mths)

Install and Configure a Linux based network between Head Office and 3 branch offices. All sites hosting Ubuntu Kylin Servers connected using OpenVPN. Client PC's were either migrated from Windows to Ubuntu or reconfigured to connect to the new infrastructure. Setup ABC Inventory software on factory premises including training staff.

Client: Barnens Hus (Retailer)

Umea, Sweden (6yrs)

Responsible for handling in all queries regarding desktops, servers and networks. Software and hardware installations, build new computers and upgrading. Technical support for home and small business networks. Troubleshooting of wired and wireless networks. System security, backups and data recovery.

Client: Robertssons Grav AB (Construction)

Storuman, Sweden (3yrs 6mths)

Supporting users via the telephone and by email. Management and configuration of SBS 2003. Assistance with training of staff and compiling procedural documentation before translation. Applying patches and updates in accordance with company procedures. All duties in relation to the day to day running of a small IT Dept.

IT Contractor-Umbrella (UK)

Jan 2001 - Sept 2003

Client: Hackney Council (Serco ITNet)

Hackney, London, UK (12mths)

2nd Line support of all council departments scattered around the Hackney area.

Client: NHS St George's Hospital

Tooting Broadway, London, UK (12mths)

1st and 2nd Line IT support of medical staff and doctors in a busy hospital. Account creation and maintenance, floor walking, training users on new software and other daily IT related work.

Education, Training and Qualifications

360GSP	Course	Microsoft Server 2012 R2 70-410
		Microsoft Server 2012 R2 70-411
		Microsoft Server 2012 R2 70-412
		CCNA Routing and Switching 200-125
Idea-Store Canary Wharf	Course	Introduction Prince 2 Project Management
Learning Tree Courses	(Passed)	336 - Unix Introduction, 436 - Unix Server Administration for the
		Enterprise, 541 - Apache Web Server
Stepney Green Secondary	GCE 'O' Level	Physics, Chemistry, English Language, Biology, Geography,
School		Computer Studies, Mathematics
East Ham College of	GCE 'O' Level	Additional Mathematics, Electronics, Integrated Science
Technology		

Hobbies and Interests

Reading up about new web/infrastructure technologies or developing websites for friends and family using WordPress. Lately absorbed into Raspberry PI, Raspbian (Debian Linux) and Windows 10 IoT Core.

References

Available on request